The only witness to the crime was not even there.
The Gift is a horror, drama, thriller film directed by Sam Raimi.
Annie Wilson, young widow and mother of three, makes her living foretelling others'
futures⁠—though her own has become cloudier than even she can see.
Threatened by a client's violent husband and plagued by visions of a missing local woman, Annie finds herself pulled
into a thicket of lies and deception in which her extraordinary gift may ultimately get her killed.
Annie Wilson, played by Cate Blanchett.
Buddy Cole, played by Giovanni Ribisi.
Donnie Barksdale, played by Keanu Reeves.
Jessica King, played by Katie Holmes.
Wayne Collins, played by Greg Kinnear.
Valerie Barksdale, played by Hilary Swank.
The Gift is a 2000 American supernatural thriller film directed by Sam Raimi, and starring Cate
Blanchett, Keanu Reeves, Giovanni Ribisi, Hilary Swank, Katie Holmes, and Greg Kinnear.
It centers on a single mother in rural Georgia who becomes involved in a local
missing person case after she experiences a psychic vision.
The screenplay was written by Billy Bob Thornton and Tom Epperson based
on the alleged psychic experiences of Thornton's mother.
The film explores themes of small town, sheriff,
dreams, fortune teller, nightmare.
The tone is intense and mind_bending and dark.